Guide to the College of Engineering and Architecture Photographs 1964-1987
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
College of Engineering and Architecture Photographs
1964-1987
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
PC 144
Washington State University. College of Engineering and Architecture
4.25 Linear feet of Shelf Space 9 boxes Approximately 4000 images
The images were taken by employees of the Engineering Extension office of the College of Engineering and Architecture at Washington State University, and document the programs, research, and day-to-day life of the faculty, students, and staff of the College of Engineering and Architecture.
The departments which became the College of Engineering and Architecture at Washington State University were in place when the school opened in 1892, with the first graduates in 1897. In 1946, a reorganization established the Washington State Insitute of Technology as the entity which included the academic departments as the College of Engineering, the School of Mines, the Division of Industrial Research and the Division of Industrial Service. The Instutute was again reorganized in July 1966 into a College of Engineering with academic departments, a Research Division and a Technical Extension Service. In 1984, it was redefined as the College of Engineering and Architecture.
The images were taken by employees of the Engineering Extension office, and document the programs, research, and day-to-day life of the faculty, students, and staff of the College of Engineering and Architecture. Many of the originals to photographs found in Quest and other Engineering and Architecture publications can be found within this collection.
The photographs in this collection are maintained in their original order. This consists of one major chronological series of contact strips and negatives, followed by two smaller chronological series. These series are identified by the creators of those images: David C. Flaherty (Series 1), Brian T. Harvey (Series 2), or Harvey and Sue Ehrstine (Series 3).
The majority of the prints and negatives are contact sheets or strips mounted on paper; these frequently have notes from the College identifying them and have thus been retained exactly as they came to MASC. Photographs prior to 1970 have little to no labeling.
This collection is open and available for research use.
This collection was donated to the Washington State University (WSU) Libraries' Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC) on August 16th, 1990 by Kathleen Warren of WSU's College of Engineering and Architecture (CEA). It was accessioned as UA1990-05. The collection was received in a sequence of 29 large three-ring binders, which were discarded during processing.
MASC holds a few other collections of photographs from the College of Engineering and Architecture.
PC 143 is a subsequent continuation of these CEA photographs.
UA1990-37 (as of yet unprocessed) consists of a scrapbook and a small box of loose photographs.
MASC also holds a 1926 College of Engineering scrapbook as PC 94.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State University. College of Engineering and Architecture. -- Photographs.
Engineering -- Photographs.; Architecture -- Photographs.
Science; Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
- Series 1: Flaherty images
  - 1964- (Box-folder 1/1, Pages 1-25)
  - undated (Box-folder 1/2, Pages 26-50)
  - -1965 (Box-folder 1/3, Pages 51-75)
  - 1965- (Box-folder 1/4, Pages 76-100)
  - undated (Box-folder 1/5, Pages 101-125)
  - undated (Box-folder 1/6, Pages 126-150)
  - -1967 (Box-folder 2/7, Pages 151-175)
  - 1967- (Box-folder 2/8, Pages 176-200)
  - undated (Box-folder 2/9, Pages 201-225)
  - 1968- (Box-folder 2/10, Pages 226-250)
  - 1968 (Box-folder 2/11, Pages 251-275)
  - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2/12, Pages 276-300)
  - 1969 (Box-folder 2/13, Pages 301-325)
  - 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3/14, Pages 326-350)
  - 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/15, Pages 351-375)
  - 1971 (Box-folder 3/16, Pages 376-400)
  - 1971 (Box-folder 3/17, Pages 401-425)
  - 1971-1972 (Box-folder 3/18, Pages 426-450)
  - 1972-1973 (Box-folder 4/19, Pages 451-475)
  - 1973 (Box-folder 4/20, Pages 476-500)
  - 1973 (Box-folder 4/21, Pages 501-525)
  - 1973-1974 (Box-folder 4/22, Pages 526-550)
  - 1974 (Box-folder 4/23, Pages 551-575)
  - 1974 (Box-folder 4/24, Pages 576-600)
  - 1974-1975 (Box-folder 5/25, Pages 601-625)
  - 1974-1975 (Box-folder 5/26, Pages 626-650)
  - 1975 (Box-folder 5/27, Pages 651-675)
  - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 5/28, Pages 676-700)
  - 1976 (Box-folder 5/29, Pages 701-726)
  - 1976-1977 (Box-folder 5/30, Pages 750-775)
  - 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/31, Pages 776-800)
  - 1979 (Box-folder 6/32, Pages 801-825)
  - 1979 (Box-folder 6/33, Pages 826-850)
  - 1979-1980 (Box-folder 6/34, Pages 851-875)
  - 1980 (Box-folder 6/35, Pages 876-900)
  - 1980 (Box-folder 6/36, Pages 901-925)
  - 1980-1981 (Box-folder 6/37, Pages 926-950)
  - 1981-1982 (Box-folder 6/38, Pages 951-975)
  - 1982-1983 (Box-folder 7/39, Pages 976-1050)
  - 1983 (Box-folder 7/40, Pages 1051-1100)
  - 1983-1984 (Box-folder 7/41, Pages 1101-1150)
  - 1984 (Box-folder 7/42, Pages 1151-1200)
  - 1984-1985 (Box-folder 7/43, Pages 1201-1250)
  - 1985-1986 (Box-folder 8/44, Pages 1251-1300)
  - 1986-1987 (Box-folder 8/45, Pages 1301-1350)
  - 1987 (Box-folder 8/46, Pages 1351-1381)
- Series 2: Harvey images
  - 1974-1976 (Box-folder 8/47, Pages 1-100)
  - 1976-1980 (Box-folder 8/48, Pages 101-200)
  - 1980-1985 (Box-folder 9/49, Pages 201-275)
- Series 3: Ehrstine and Harvey images
  - 1979-1984 (Box-folder 9/50-51, Pages unnum.)